vandyke.com 2018-11-06

# VanDyke Software - Privacy

### Privacy Policy

  1. General Terms
  2. Types and Methods of Information Collection
  3. Cookies
  4. What We Do with the Information We Collect
  5. Marketing
  6. Profiling and Automated Decision-Making
  7. Sharing Information
  8. Sharing Information Outside of the EEA
  9. Your Rights
  10. When We Delete Data
  11. Security
  12. Links to Other Websites
  13. Changes to the Privacy Statement
  14. Contact Details

**1\. General Terms**  
VanDyke Software, Inc. ("VanDyke") is a data controller of personal information collected and processed through its business activities. VanDyke respects your privacy. This Privacy Policy discloses the following privacy practices for [www.vandyke.com](https://www.vandyke.com/index.php) ("Website") and other related business activities. In collecting and using information about you, we adhere to the following principles:

  * We collect information about you only when you provide it voluntarily.
  * We never share the information you provide to third parties without your approval.
  * We do not sell or rent email or mailing lists to third parties.

**2\. Types and Methods of Information Collection**  
We collect your personal information in order to provide and continually improve our products and services. Here are the types of information we gather:

_Information You Give Us:_ We receive and store information you provide in relation to doing business with VanDyke. Once you create an account, log in, or submit information through the Website we will know who you are and your activities on the Website and information about you and/or your company may be recorded on our systems. Below are examples of what we collect:

  * your name
  * company name
  * email address
  * postal address
  * job function
  * invoicing/payment
  * country where you are based or purchasing/registering our products from
  * telephone number
  * information relating to network access and network security
  * your comments/questions
  * products/services you are interested in 

_Automatic Information:_ We automatically receive and store certain types of information when you use our Website. Like many websites, we use cookies and other unique identifiers and we obtain certain types of information when your web browser or devices access our Website. Below are examples of what we collect:

  * the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet
  * login credentials
  * content interaction information, such as product downloads
  * purchase and product use history
  * the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through, and from our website

_Information From Other Sources:_ We also receive information about you from other sources. Below are examples of the information we receive:

  * transaction information from resellers or distributors
  * transaction information from merchant services vendors
  * export verification information

**3\. Cookies**  
To enable our systems to recognize your browser or device and to provide services to you, we use cookies. For more information about cookies and how we use them, please read our Cookie Usage.

**4\. What We Do with the Information We Collect**  
VanDyke will use your Personal Information only for legitimate business purposes (i.e., to provide and improve our products and services). We also use Personal Information for:

  * internal record keeping
  * internal business processes
  * product and service development and support
  * delivery of products or services and/or order fulfillment including through our resellers, distributors, and other agents
  * compliance with our own legal obligations
  * compliance with export control regulations
  * license verification
  * market research
  * marketing our own products and services (including upgrades) to you 

**5\. Marketing**  
If you are a customer of ours or you have previously asked us for information on our products and services (such as subscribing to our What's New feed), then we may send you information about VanDyke products and services. If you decide that you no longer wish to receive these emails from us, please follow the unsubscribe link in one of our email messages.

Please note that we may send out periodic emails, including to inform you of a technical service or security issues relating to a product or service you have requested or purchased, or confirming your request or purchase of a product or service. You will not be able to choose to unsubscribe from these communications, as they are considered an essential part of the service you have chosen. 

**6\. Profiling and Automated Decision-Making**  
VanDyke does not process personal data for profiling or automated decision-making.

**7\. Sharing Information**  
We will not share your contact information with other organizations for commercial or solicitation purposes. VanDyke shares customers' information only as described below. In all instances, VanDyke requires that personal information be processed in accordance with this Privacy Notice and as permitted by applicable data protection laws:

  * **Transactions Involving Third Parties:** You can order VanDyke products and services from third-party resellers and distributors. These parties have access to personal information as needed to provide VanDyke products and services.
  * **Third Party Service Providers:** We employ other companies and individuals to perform certain functions on our behalf. Examples include: sending e-mail, processing payments, and transmitting content. These third-party service providers have access to personal information needed to perform their functions.
  * **Disclosure required by law:** Please be aware that in certain circumstances, it is possible that personal information may be subject to disclosure pursuant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, or orders. We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law.

**8\. Sharing Information Outside of the EEA**  
Whenever we transfer personal information to countries outside of the European Economic Area in the course of sharing information as set out above, we will ensure that the information is transferred in accordance with this Privacy Notice and as permitted by the applicable laws on data protection.

**9\. Your Rights**  
You have the right to see the Personal Information we hold about you and to ask us to:

  * make any changes to ensure that any Personal Information we hold about you is accurate and up to date,
  * erase or stop processing any Personal Information we hold about you where there is no longer a legal ground for us to hold it, or
  * in some cases, transfer any information we hold about you to a specified third party. 

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us.

**10\. When We Delete Data**  
We keep your personal information to enable your continued use of VanDyke products and services, for as long as it is required in order to fulfill the relevant purposes described in this Privacy Notice, as may be required by law such as for tax and accounting purposes, or as otherwise communicated to you.

**11\. Security**  
No transmission over the Internet is 100% secure, and when you provide your information to us over the Internet, you do so at your own risk. We store all collected electronic data in a password-protected database. We maintain our own email and mailing lists. High-grade encryption is used to protect your credit card information.

**12\. Links to Other Websites**  
The Website sometimes include links to other websites which are not within our control. Once you have left the Website, we cannot be held responsible for the content of other websites or the protection and privacy of any information which you provide to those websites. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question. 

**13\. Changes to the Privacy Statement**  
We may update the Privacy Policy from time to time and you are responsible for reviewing the most current version. The date of the last update to the Privacy Policy is stated at the end of the Privacy Policy. By continuing to use the Website, you accept any updates to the Privacy Policy.

**14\. Contact Details**  
If you wish to review or have questions regarding your information, please email us at legal@vandyke.com.

This Privacy Statement was last updated: 28 August 2018.
